Sincro: wyxchari
【翻译】巴蛮子sz
【时间轴】巴蛮子sz
【校对】巴蛮子sz
His face, his hair - look at it!
他的脸，他的头发，你看!
He's breathing...
他还在呼吸...
...and the TARDIS seems to be normal.
...而且TARDIS看起来很正常
Ben, what are we going to do? We can't just leave the Doctor there.
Ben, 我们该怎么办? 我们不能把博士扔那儿不管.
What, him? The Doctor?
什么, 他? 是博士?
Ben, do you remember what he said in the tracking room?
Something about "This old body of mine is wearing a bit thin. "
Ben, 你记得他在跟踪室内说过什么吗? 好像说＂我的旧身体穿了身新皮囊. "
So he gets himself a new one?
这么说他有了个新的?
But it's impossible!
但这不可能啊!
Not so long ago we'd have been saying that about a lot of things.
不久以前，我们还对好多事情都说不可能
It's over.
过去了
What are we going to do?
我们该做点什么?
It is the Doctor. I know it is... I think.
他是博士. 我就知道... 我觉得.
It's not only his face that's changed
- he doesn't even act like him.
不仅仅是他的脸变了 - 他的行为也不像.
Come on, it's time we sorted this out.
来吧，我们把这事搞清楚.
Now look here!
现在看这儿!
Hold that.
停住.
And tilt it.
斜点儿
Have you done with this?
完事了吗?
Put it down, put it down.
放下，放下.
Now, what's the game?
现在，玩什么游戏?
Ah!
啊!
The crusades, from Saladin.
十字军，撒拉丁
The Doctor was a great collector, wasn't he!
博士是个收藏家啊!
But you're the Doctor!
但你就是博士啊!
Oh, I don't look like him.
哦，我看着不像他.
Who are we?
我们是谁?
Don't you know?
你不知道吗?
Extermination!
Now look, the Doctor always wore this.
So if you're him, it should fit now, shouldn't it?
看，博士总戴着这个，如果你是他，这个应该大小合适，对不对?
There - that settles it.
看 - 掉下来了.
I'd like to see a butterfly fit into a chrysalis case
after it's spread its wings.
我想看看蝴蝶展开翅膀后怎么适应它的蛹
Then you did change!
你真的变了!
Life depends on change... and renewal.
生命依赖于变化... 和新生.
The Doctor kept a diary, didn't he?
博士持有一本日记，对吧?
Yes.
是的.
I thought so. Now, I wonder where?
我记得是，不过现在在哪儿呢?
I wonder where?
在哪儿呢?
He's a very different Doctor, Ben.
他真跟博士有点不同, Ben.
Yeah, maybe. Just where do we stand, though?
嗯, 很可能. 不过我们现在到底什么情况?
Doctor? Doctor, what's going to happen to us?
博士? 博士, 我们会怎样?
I think... I think we must have landed for sometime.
I think it's time we went for a stroll.
我觉得... 我觉得我们着陆有一阵子了. 我觉得我们该出去逛逛了.
But you don't know where we've landed!
但你都不知道我们着陆到哪里了!
No, you haven't checked the oxygen or the temperature or anything!
别，你还没有检查氧气和温度，什么都没还没检查!
Oxygen density one-seven-two, radiation nil, temperature...
eighty-six - strong suggestion of mercury deposits.
氧气浓度172，辐射零，温度86. 有较强的水银沉淀.
Satisfied, Ben? Now, are you two coming or are you not?
满意了吗, Ben? 现在，你们两个来还是不来?
He does know us! He said "Ben", didn't you hear him?
他真认识我们! 他喊你 "Ben", 听到了吧?
Yeah, I heard.
是的, 我听到了
Are you coming, you two?
来不来，你俩?
Hello?
哈罗?
Hello? Is there anyone there? Hello?
哈罗? 有人吗? 哈罗?
Hello? Why don't they come?
哈罗? 他们怎么还不来?
Ah, so you've come at last. I'm from Earth. I'm the Examin...
啊, 你终于来了. 我从地球来的. 我是监察员...
"Earth Examiner. Accord every access. Vulcan. "
"地球监察员. 授予所有权限. Vulcan. "
Whoa, they're hot!
喔, 好热!
Hmm, do you think the air's like this everywhere?
唔, 是不是到处的空气都像这样?
Nah - might be just round here.
Don't want too many lung full of it, I know that.
不 - 可能只是这一片才这样. 别使劲吸气, 我知道的.
Here, when I was a kid, we used to live opposite a brewery.
You could take a walk and get tipsy all in one go!
我小的时候住在一家酒坊对面. 还没走完一趟人就醉了!
It's beautiful!
好美啊!
No, don't touch it, Polly!
别，别碰, Polly!
I wasn't going to.
我没打算碰.
No, it's quicksilver - it gets through the pores.
这是水银 - 会从这些气泡里面出来.
Where is the Doctor, or whatever he is, got to?
博士要去哪儿啊? - 就算他是博士吧
So the murdered man was the real Examiner?
所以被谋杀的人就是真的监察员?
Well, didn't you see who did it?
那么，你有没有看到是谁干的?
The Doctor got this button though.
博士, 这里多了颗纽扣.
Well, I think it's pretty dull around here.
I don't know why we don't just go back to the TARDIS.
我觉得这挺无聊的. 我不明白我们为什么不回到 TARDIS 去.
Doctor, are you going to let them think you're the real Examiner?
博士，你是想让他们觉得你就是真正的监察员吗?
Well, won't that be dangerous?
嗯，那会不会比较危险?
Look, why don't you stop blowing that thing and talk to us properly?
看，你能不能不再吹那个，认真跟我们说说?
Ben!
Now don't you start - it's bad enough with him!
你现在别说话 - 跟他在一起就够糟的了!
Well, he hasn't done anything.
他什么也没做.
No, that's just the trouble!
He knows what happened back at the TARDIS,
不，那就是麻烦所在! 他知道那会儿 TARDIS 里发生了什么
yet will he tell us? Will he come out and say?
Will he admit to being the Doctor?
他会告诉我们吗? 他会站出来说? 他会承认他就是博士?
Come in!
请进!
I am Hensell - the Governor.
If Earth had seen fit to warn us you were coming...
If Earth didn't warn you we were coming, Governor,
they must have had a very good reason. I wonder what it was?
如果地球没告诉你，总督，他们一定有一个很好理由. 我很好奇到底是什么?
Now look here - I run this Colony. I'm entitled to know
why you've come to Vulcan. What is your brief?
你看 - 我负责这块基地. 我有权知道你为什么到 Vulcan 来. 简单说说?
I am the Examiner.
我是监察员.
Why are you here?
为什么来这儿?
To examine. And I intend to start my examination at once!
监察. 我现在就要开始检查!
Someone's leaked reports about these rebel groups
- that's it, isn't it?
有人密报说这里有人叛乱，是为了这个吧，是吗?
There is Lesterson's capsule.
应该是 Lesterson 的那个舱体.
Internal affairs are my business, Bragen.
Please don't interfere!
内部事物归我管， Bragen. 请不要来干扰我们!
Please go on.
请继续.
The capsule. It was found in a mercury swamp.
It must have been here for centuries before the Earth colony arrived.
这个舱体，是在一个水银沼泽里发现的. 可能在那里已经几个世纪了, 比地球殖民者还早
I felt it might be dangerous, it might contain bacteria.
我觉得它可能很危险, 它可能带有细菌.
I shall examine the capsule.
我应该检查一下这个舱体
Where did you get this?
你在哪里得到这个的?
It dropped from the capsule.
从舱体上掉下来的.
Dropped?
掉下来?
Yes, when it was being hauled into the laboratory.
是的, 把它拖进实验室的时候.
But, you can see! This metal could revolutionise space travel.
不过，你看! 这种金属可以会对我们的太空旅行技术产生革命性影响.
That's why I'm insisting that we open it.
Well, who knows what other marvels there may be inside?
这也是为什么我坚持要打开舱体. 谁知道里面还有什么其它神奇的东西?
But Lesterson, I didn't think you could open it?
不过 Lesterson, 我没想到你能打开它?
Well, I have a theory. I'm convinced that the opening mechanism
on the other side is either here, or here.
我有一个理论. 我推断打开的方法是在两端，要么这边，要么这边.
Extermination...
终结!...
Now, my theory is that I can insert a laser ray in this ridge here.
我的理论是可以在这个背脊处注入激光束.
The ray spreads, fuses the opening device and gets us in.
光束散开, 触发开门设备，我们就可以进去了.
Examiner, I shall have to make it your responsibility.
监察员, 我觉得该你来决策了.
A laser? Why not? It shouldn't be too difficult.
激光? 没问题啊，不会太难.
Well, we'll try the other side.
我们来试试另外一边.
Hmm, it's a bit... disappointing.
唔, 有一点... 让人失望.
Not really. This is just an entry bay, isn't it?
不会. 这只是门廊, 对吧?
Yes, I... I suppose so.
是的... 我觉得是.
Well, this doesn't get us very far does it?
那并没有让我们走多远是吧?
Ah, getting into the rest of the capsule will take time, Governor.
进到舱体其它部分就需要时间了，总督.
Well, can't you use that torch thing again?
That must be an opening door.
你不能再用一下那个光束吗?那肯定是一个门.
Well, I should have to measure it up
and find out where the lock mechanism is.
我得考察一下，看看锁机关在哪儿.
And I think we'll leave it for tonight.
我觉得今晚就到此为止吧.
Leave it?
到此为止?
Leave it for tonight? But what did we come here for?
就这样了? 那我们来这儿干什么?
That is my decision, Governor.
这是我的决定，总督.
But, good heavens above, man!
但是，苍天在上!
Two hundred years, you say, this has been buried?
两百年，你说它被埋了?
Oh, at least. Now, there must be something in the inner compartment.
哦，至少有. 里面的隔间里一定有什么东西.
We shall be able to find out where it came from originally.
我们应该可以搞明白它是从哪里来的.
It didn't come from this planet - Vulcan.
它并不是来自这个星球 - Vulcan.
Oh no, no, no. The metal is quite alien.
哦，不不不. 这个金属很外星.
Alien, yes. Very alien. Goodnight.
外星，是的. 非常外星. 晚安.
What's he up to now?
他这是要干什么?
Ben, we're not going to let him out of our sight.
Ben, 不要让他离开我们的视线.
Well, Lesterson, you got your way. Was it worth
sending for this Examiner? This idiotic Examiner?
好了，Lesterson, 你有路子. 不过你找来这监察员值得吗? 就这个愚蠢的家伙?
I didn't send for him. I thought you did.
不是我找来的. 我还以为是你呢.
Why don't you let me talk to the Examiner, Hensell?
I can find out what's he's here for.
你为什么不让我跟监察员说话，Hensell? 我能找出他来这里的原因.
No, no, no, no, you keep away from him.
We'll leave him to work with Lesterson here.
不不不, 你离他远点. 我们让他跟 Lesterson 呆一起吧.
We've all got enough to do without having to worry about
some amateur critic from Earth interfering.
我们都有太多事情要做，负担不起来自地球的业余批评.
But with five minutes, I _...
但只要５分钟, 我 _...
You heard what I said, Quinn.
You won't mind keeping the Examiner busy, Lesterson?
你听到我的话了, Quinn. 你不介意让监察员忙得团团转吧, Lesterson?
我不介意你跟他做什么 ... 只要他的鼻子别到我的事情里面来到处嗅.
I don't mind what you do with him so long as you keep his nose...
out of our business.
Yes. All right.
好. 没问题.
All right. Well, we shall talk about it tomorrow.
就这样. 我们明早再讨论.
Ben!
What?
Shh! He's in the corridor.
嘘! 他在走廊里.
Who is?
谁?
The Doctor, you clod! Come on - quick!
博士, 你个笨蛋! 过来 - 快!
He's going towards Lesterson's lab.
他往 Lesterson 的实验室去了.
Of course - to the space capsule!
当然 - 那个太空舱!
Come on.
来吧
Polly, Ben, come in and meet the Daleks.
Polly, Ben, 进来见见 Daleks.
What?
什么?
The Daleks.
Daleks.
You could have opened this before.
你以前就打开过这个.
These two pieces of metal are identical.
这两块金属是一样的
I knew I should find them here.
我就知道能在这里找到它们
Ah, they look harmless, not very lively.
啊, 他们看起来是无害的, 并不活跃.
Two hundred years in a swamp and you wouldn't look very lively
either. Nothing could live through that, could it?
你想什么呢? 在沼泽里呆200年，你也看起来不活跃. 没有什么东西能熬过来，是吧?
Live?
活的?
Nothing human, no.
不是人类, 不.
Doctor, look!
博士，看!
What's the matter?
怎么回事?
Well, there were three Daleks in here!
What's happened to the other one?
这里本来有三个 Daleks 的! 另外一个发生了什么?
Doctor, look!
博士, 看!
A light. A torch outside.
要光. 去外面拿个电筒.
Did you see it?
你看见了吗?
Quickly Ben, quickly!
快点 Ben, 快!
What was it?
是什么?
Can you answer me?
能回答我吗?
It was a sort of disembodied hand.
A sort of claw. It was horrible!
好像是某种脱离下来的肢体，某种爪子. 好吓人!
No. No, there's nothing.
不. 不, 什么也没有.
You were right - there were three Daleks.
你是对的 - 之前是有三个 Daleks.
Do you know what it was?
你知道那是什么?
If there were three, who moved it?
如果之前有三个，谁移动了?
Don't ask me. Lesterson?
别问我. Lesterson?
But he hadn't opened the capsule.
但他还没有打开舱体啊.
Now he said he hadn't opened it.
Lets get our facts straight.
他“说”他还没有打开．我们直接去找真相吧.
Aha, excellent! Good thinking, good thinking.
啊哈, 太棒了! 好想法，好想法.
What, does that mean you think he's been inside?
什么, 那不是说你觉得他进去过?
Perhaps he's been experimenting on the Daleks? Ah.
也许他一直在试验 Daleks? 啊
But... but they're things I...
I mean they're dead. They must be!
但是... 但他们是... 我是说他们已经死了. 肯定是!
This light is dead. Now the watch!
这盏灯是死的吧，现在看看!
Do you mean these things just need power?
你是说这些东西只是需要能量?
Now, Lesterson's fanatic. The Governor's jealous of his own position.
嗯, Lesterson 太狂热了. 总督太在乎他自己的位置
What does that suggest to you? Dunno. Hadn't thought about it.
这让你想起什么了吗? 不知道. 没想过这个.
That all is not well with this colony. Add to that one Dalek!
这个基地所有事情都不太好，现在又多出来个 Dalek!
Oh, blimey, you don't half make mountains, don't you? One Dalek?
噢, 天啊, 你不用这样疑神疑鬼的吧，不就一个 Dalek?
Yes! All that is needed to wipe out this entire colony.
是的! 只要一个就可以彻底荡平整个基地了.
Examiner?
监察员?
Bragen, don't you ever knock before you enter a room?
Bragen, 你进屋之前从不敲门吗?
I'm sorry if I disturbed you.
I was expecting to find the Examiner here - not you Quinn.
我很抱歉打扰了你. 我以为能在这里找到监察员，不是来找你 Quinn 的
Well, he's not here.
The Governor gave express instructions that you were not to contact the Examiner
总督已经明确说过你不能跟监察员接触
I find you here. I'm sure you can offer some suitable explanation.
但我发现你在这里，相信你能提供一个合适的解释.
I can. But not to you.
我能. 但不是对你.
The Examiner is missing. He must be found immediately.
监察员不见了. 得马上找到他.
Doctor, look, if they're that dangerous,
what are you going to do about it?
博士，你看, 如果他们有那么危险的话，你打算拿他们怎么办?
Save my breath. Would Lesterson listen? Uh, uh. Lesterson listen...
让我喘口气. Lesterson 会听吗? 哦, 哦. Lesterson listen....
Exercises the tongue. Try it! Lesterson listen, Lesterson listen....
锻炼一下舌头. 试试 Lesterson listen...
Look, they think you're the Examiner, order them to destroy the Daleks! Well, chuck your weight about.
看，他们认为你是监察员, 让他们把 Daleks 都销毁吧! 就这样，把你的权利都用上.
Lesterson listen, Lesterson listen, Lesterson listen...
What do you think you're doing in here?
你觉得你在干什么?
Listen, listen...
Who gave you permission?
谁给你的权限?
Read this! Aloud!
读读这个! 大声读!
Accord every access.
授予所有权限.
Exactly! It doesn't say 'except your laboratory' anywhere,
does it? Unless it's in micro-print.
正确! 它并没说＂除了你的实验室＂，是吧? 除非使用小号字印的.
I should have been asked first!
我应该先问问的!
Where is the third Dalek?
第三个 Dalek 哪里去了?
I don't know what you're talking about!
我不知道你在说什么!
You opened up the capsule without permission.
You found the inner compartment containing three Daleks
你没经过允许就打开了舱体. 你发现了隔间里有三个 Daleks
You took one of them away and you hid it!
你弄走了一个，藏了起来!
Hid it? What... what nonsense!
藏起来? 简直... 胡说八道!
May I ask what all this is about?
我能问问这是怎么回事吗?
We opened an inner compartment in the capsule,
and Lesterson had already been in there.
我们打开舱体里面的隔间时，Lesterson 早就进去过了.
I don't deny that.
我不否认这个.
And he's nicked a Dalek!
他藏匿了一个 Dalek!
Dalek?
It's the name the Examiner has given to two metal creations
that I've discovered inside the capsule.
这是监察员给这种金属生物起的名字，就我在舱体里面发现的那两个生物.
And they're dangerous. Evil.
他们很危险，很邪恶.
Lumps of metal! Quite inactive.
金属肿块而已! 非常不活跃.
That's what you think, mate. If you'd seen...
那是你的想法，伙计．如果你看过...
I consider it's my duty as a scientist to... to examine and investigate these objects.
我想这是我作为一个科学家的指责，检查和调查这些东西
Now please, all of you, keep out of my laboratory.
Keep your hands off my experiments!
现在请离开我的实验室，你们全部．别想染指我的实验!
Those 'lumps of metal' - Daleks -
I want them broken up, or melted down.
Up, or down, I don't care which, but destroyed!
那些＂金属肿块＂ - Daleks - 我期望他们坏掉，溶掉．我不关心什么方法，但要毁掉．
I refuse to allow it.
我不允许
I'm an Earth Examiner - I demand it.
我是地球监察员 - 我要求这样.
You're exceeding your authority.
这已经超过你的授权范围了.
Perhaps we should ask the Governor about that?
I wish to see him immediately!
或许我们该问问总督的意见?我要马上见他!
That might be difficult.
那可能比较困难.
But not impossible. Ben, Polly.
但不是不可能. Ben, Polly.
Could he stop the experiments?
他能够停掉这些实验不?
I don't know. It's none of your business.
You go and get Janley and then come back here.
我不知道. 这不关你们的事. 你去叫一下 Janley，然后一起过来
We haven't... haven't got any time to waste.
Now go on man, quickly, quickly!
我们没有... 没有时间浪费. 去吧，快，快!
I'd advise a little discretion in your investigations.
It's not a very good time, just now.
但我建议你调查的时候慎重一下. 现在不是一个好的时间点.
With all these disturbances...
当前这些风风雨雨...
Disturbances?
风风雨雨?
Yes, minor acts of sabotage, rebel cliques, secret newspapers,
nothing important you understand, but it keeps the Governor busy.
是的, 一些小的破坏活动, 结党叛乱, 秘密报纸, 没什么太重要的. 但也让总督闲不下来
I have no doubt he'll tell you about it himself
when I arrange your meeting with him.
我毫不怀疑他会自己跟你说的, 我安排一下你们的会见．
When will that be?
打算在什么时候?
Ah, he's going on a tour of the perimeter of the colony.
I'll... I'll find out if he can see you before he goes.
啊, 他先要对基地周边巡视一下... 我看看他去之前能不能见你一下.
Thank you.
谢谢你.
Ah, it's a...
啊, 这是个...
He won't stop me experimenting. There must be some way to bring you back to life - and I'm going to find it.
他可阻止不了我的实验．一定有什么方法让你活过来 - 我要找出来
Here, I bet old Charlie Bragen did it!
我打赌是那个老Charlie Bragen 干的!
Charlie?
是叫 Charlie 吗?
Well Fred wouldn't suit him would it?
但是 Fred 这个名字不太适合他啊，是吧?
If he did do it, do you think it was his own idea?
I mean - he could have been under orders.
如果是他做的，你觉得那是他自己的想法吗? 我是说 - 他可能是收到了命令
You mean from the Governor? Ah, I don't know.
What do you think, Doctor?
你说可能来自总督? 啊, 我不知道. 你怎么想，博士?
Oh, yes. Yes of course. Let's... let's consider this button for a moment.
哦，是的. 当然. 我们... 我们先来看一下这个纽扣.
It's the only clue we've got to the murderer of the Examiner.
The real Examiner.
这是我们手上关于监察员被害的唯一线索，那个真监察员.
Hmm. And who asked for him to come?
唔. 谁要求他来这里的?
Hmm. Well, Lesterson's crackers about that capsule.
He wouldn't want anyone nosing about.
唔，看Lesterson对于那个舱体的疯狂举动，他不想让任何人打听.
Bragen said the Governor's been having trouble.
Bragen 说总督那边一直麻烦缠身.
Naw, rule him out. Governors are all the same, he wouldn't ask for help.
好，先排除他. 总督都是一样的，他不会请求援助.
If he sent the word it would look as if he couldn't do the job properly.
如果他发这样的信息，会让他看起来不能正确自己处理.
Yes.
是的
Oh, well, I vote we go back to the TARDIS,
I've had enough of this dump.
哦噢，我建议先回到 TARDIS, 我有点受够了.
Have you? What about the Daleks?
是吗? Daleks 怎么办?
Well, they're dead.
他们是死的.
Well, what about that thing we saw in the capsule
- that was alive all right.
我们在舱体里面看到的那个东西是怎么一回事 - 那可是活的.
Well, can't explain that.
没法解释那个.
I can. And that's why we have to stay!
我能. 而且那就是为什么我们还不能走!
Ugly-looking brutes aren't they?
Hey, what's he want to muck about with them for?
他们很丑陋的畜生是吧? 嘿, 他到底瞎倒腾这些干什么呢?
Leave well alone, that's what I say.
别管这个了, 要我说.
You're a fine one to be a research assistant. Leave well alone?
There'll be no progress on this planet with people like you around.
你就适合做个助手．别管这个了? 如果这个星球上都是你这样的人, 我们不会有任何进展.
We're doing all right as we are. Or we were until your lot
came along stirring things up
我们一直干得不错，或者说曾经不错，直到你们这些家伙出来把事情搅乱. 你们跑不掉, 你知道吧
You won't get away with it, you know.
The Governor knows all about you rebels.
He'll smash the lot of you when he's ready.
你们跑不掉的，你知道吧?总督对于你们叛乱的事情全知道, 当他准备好之后会碾碎你们.
Governor?
总督?
Yeah, the Governor!
对, 总督!
He couldn't smash...
他不可能碾碎...
Will you be quiet! Where do you both think you are?
This is a scientific laboratory. Kindly keep your politics out of it.
能不能安静一下! 你们俩以为自己是谁? 这是间科学实验室，请别把政治带进来.
Come on, Resno. Man, get on with it. We haven't got all day.
快点, Resno. 伙计, 动起来. 我们没有那么多时间.
We've got to get this working before the Examiner stops us.
He's got some phobia about these...
我们得在监察员叫停之前搞定这个. 他有点害怕这些个...
Daleks! I know the misery they cause - the destruction.
Daleks! 我可知道他们能导致什么悲剧 - 完全的毁灭
Well? Where is the Governor? What did he say?
总督在哪儿? 他说了什么?
哦?
He sends his apologies Examiner. He can't see you tonight,
but he hopes to see you first thing in the morning.
他传达了歉意, 监察员．他今晚不能见你, 但期望明早第一个见你.
Well, it might not wait that long, Char... ah, Bragen.
哦, 但也许不用等那么久, Charl ... 哦, Bragen.
It will have to.
还真早不了.
Excuse me.
抱歉.
Where are you going?
你要去哪儿?
To see the Governor, of course.
当然是去见总督.
I'm afraid that's not possible. Once his door is closed, no-one,
not even you, Examiner, is allowed into his room!
恐怕不可能．一旦他的门关上了, 没有人, 即便是你监察员, 也不允许进入他的房间!
Very well.
好吧.
Thank you. Until the morning then.
谢谢. 那就明早吧.
What happens now?
这里发生了什么?
I shall radio Earth. I'll get Earth to back me.
我要联系地球，得让地球支持我
Connecting now.
开始连接.
All connections responding.
所有连接正常.
Nothing at all?
完全没反应?
No.
It's moving!
开始动了!
Now, note this, Janley. Number one attachment with sucker
stick responding. Number two attachment not moving.
现在记下来, Janley. 一号附着物吸盘有反应. 二号附着物没动.
Number three attachment with lens responding.
Watch these meters, Resno.
三号附着物镜头有反应. 看看这些读数, Resno.
Still responding.
还有反应.
Now, it's reasonable to assume that this the sucker stick
acts like some kind of a hand.
现在, 有理由假定这个有吸盘的棍子有着手一样的功能.
It's all right - don't be alarmed.
We've only introduced temporary power.
没事 - 别大惊小怪. 我们只给了临时的能量.
We shall have to be able to open it up
before we could find how it works permanently.
我们得打开它才能彻底搞明白它是怎么工作的.
It's a bit frightening.
这东西有一点吓人.
Yes. Now, I cannot think what this short stubby arm is for.
是的. 现在我没法想出这个短臂是干什么的.
Could the lens attachment be an eye?
这些镜头会是眼睛吗?
Yes, yes, yes, yes. Now it's quite possible that this, ah, Dalek...
Now there must be some kind of directing influence.
是的, 是的. 很有可能是． 啊, 这个叫做Dalek的东西... 肯定有某种指挥系统
There may even be a simplified brain. Positronic,
I shouldn't wonder. If only we could open it up!
这里甚至可能有一个简化的大脑. 正电子的, 我不会奇怪的. 要是我们能打开它就好了!
Now what?
现在怎么办?
Everything functioning here.
所有都可以工作了.
Yes. Well, perhaps the power is leaking away somewhere.
We'll... we'll try again.
是的, 也许某个地方有能量泄露. 我们再试试.
Look at the eye-stick!
看它的眼睛!
It's watching us!
它在看我们!
Don't be absurd.
荒谬.
It was. I saw it!
真的. 我看见了!
You can't use the phrase 'watching us'. You'll have us
believing that th... the thing has intelligence next.
你不能说＂在看我们＂. 你这样会让我们觉得... 这东西好像有智力似的.
Now, get on with your work, man!
继续干活去吧!
I know you're there.
我就知道你在这里.
Examiner, thank goodness, it's you.
I've been trying to talk to you ever since you got here.
监察员, 谢天谢地, 是你啊. 你一到这里我就想来跟你谈谈.
What's happening here? You again.
这里发生了什么? 又是你.
What do you want?
你想要什么?
I found the operator unconscious.
我发现这个操作员昏迷了.
So did I! I was just looking at him, when I heard
someone move. It must have been you.
我也发现了! 我正看着他, 就听见有谁在走动了. 肯定是你.
And those?
那些是...?
I picked them up. What is all this?
我刚捡起来的. 这都是怎么了?
The cables have been cut.
这些线缆被剪断了.
This is serious. It's not just our own communications.
We're cut off from Earth as well.
这很严重. 不仅仅是内部通讯出了问题了，我们跟地球的联系也被切断了.
The only people who'd want to do that are the rebels.
想干这个的只能是那些叛乱分子.
Those muscle boys of yours had any brains,
they'd stop things like this.
你的那些四肢发达的小伙子要是有点脑子的话, 就能防止这些事情发生了.
And you say you picked these up? I suggest that
you were sabotaging the communications...
你说这个东西是你捡到的? 我觉得破坏通讯的也是你...
That's a lie!
那是瞎说!
...having first attacked one of the engineers.
I'd detain the Governor on evidence like that.
...还攻击了其中一个工程师. 有这些证据，我得让总督过一会儿再走.
I hope you're not thinking of detaining me, Bragen.
我期望你没打算监禁我, Bragen.
I've no option. I could hardly let you run around loose after this, could I?
我没得选. 发生了这样的事, 我不可能再让你乱跑, 是吧?
All right - you win this round, Bragen.
We'll see what it looks like in front of the Governor.
好吧 - 这轮你赢了. 我们看看到了总督面前怎么说.
All connections responding.
所有连接正常.
Excellent.
很好.
It's working!
行了!
Excellent. Film it, film it now, Resno.
And, note the readings, Janley.
很好. 录下来, 现在就录, Resno. 对了, 记一下数据, Janley.
It seems to be interested in you, Resno.
看来它对你有兴趣, Resno.
What's the matter with you man?
你是怎么回事?
I tell you it's intelligent. It's watching me, Lesterson.
Weighing me up! I can sense it!
我告诉你它是有智能的. 他在看着我, Lesterson. 在打量我! 我能感觉到!
Don't be a fool.
别傻了.
I don't like it I tell you.
I don't know what these things can do.
我不喜欢这样, 我跟你说．我不知道这些东西能做出什么事情来．
No, and we never shall know, shall we, unless we take film
of every reaction. Now get on with your work, man!
不, 我们永远不可能知道, 除非我们把它的每一个反应都拍下来. 继续你的工作, 伙计!
Resno!
It's all right. He isn't dead.
没事．他没死.
What happened?
发生了什么?
Knocked out by the shock waves.
被冲击波震晕了.
We must get him to the hospital. I'll go and get help.
我们必须带他去医院, 我去叫人来帮忙.
But we've got to defend Quinn.
我们要帮 Quinn 作证
Yeah, I know. He's innocent until he's proved guilty. But he is guilty.
是的,  我知道． 他是无辜的,  至少在证明他有罪之前．但他有罪.
He's the Deputy Governor!
他是副总督!
So what? I had a headmaster once who got nicked for not paying his bus fare!
And then there's the motive, don't forget the motive.
那又怎样? 我那会儿有个小头目被撸下来, 就只因为没交公交车费! 而且他这还是有动机的, 别忘了动机.
Like what for instance?
比如说是什么?
Well, he's the Deputy Governor, right? Maybe he wants to be Governor.
首先, 他是副总督, 对吧? 也许他想当总督.
Oh, that's ridiculous!
哦, 这太荒谬了!
Well, the jacket button wasn't! And he was caught red-handed
in the Communications Room with a pair of pliers
那, 外衣纽扣总不荒谬吧! 而且他在通讯室里面被抓住时手里正拿着一把钳子
And don't tell me he was plucking his eye-brows either.
别跟我说他是拿那东西来剪眉毛的.
Look, there are some people you know are all right.
You just know by looking at them.
有些人你知道他们是没有问题的，你看见他们的样子就知道.
Good morning. The enquiry is about to begin.
I've been sent to escort you.
早上好. 质询马上要开始. 我被派来带你们过去.
I am sorry I couldn't see you earlier, Examiner. Please sit down.
我很抱歉没能早点见你，监察员. 请坐.
Well, Quinn, I don't like this anymore than you do.
What have you been up to?
Quinn, 我跟你一样不喜欢这个. 你都做什么了?
Nothing. Absolutely nothing.
什么也没有做.
Well, what about Bragen's report then? These are facts, Quinn.
Now, what have you got to say about it?
那， Bragen 的报告是怎么回事? 这些是事实证据, Quinn. 现在，你还有什么要说的?
Does the engineer say I hit him?
那个工程师说是我打了他?
How could he if he was hit from behind?
他是被人从后面袭击的，他能怎么说?
Then its only circumstantial evidence.
那就只有间接证据了.
The Examiner was also attacked in the mercury swamp.
We have a button from your jacket, found in the Examiner's hand.
监察员也在水银沼泽被人袭击了. 这里有一颗你衣服上的纽扣，是在监察员手里找到的.
I can't explain that.
这个我没法解释.
I'm sure you can't!
我肯定你没法!
Examiner. You mentioned to Bragen that these machines of Lesterson's... What do you call them?
监察员，你向 Bragen 提及了 Lesterson 发现的那些机器... 你管他们叫什么来着?
I call them what they are - Daleks.
他们本来的名字 - Daleks
Ah, yes, yes, yes, Daleks. You say they could be a motive
for destroying our communications.
啊, 是是是, Daleks. 你说他们可能有动机破坏我们的通讯设施.
I do.
我说过.
Lesterson, this is a special enquiry. Now please.
Lesterson, 这是一场特别的质询. 请你...
This won't wait. You won't be disappointed!
等不急了. 你不会失望的!
You heard what I said Lesterson!
你听到我说什么了 Lesterson!
Governor, I've just completed a... an experiment which could revolutionise the whole colony. Bear with me.
总督，我已经完成了一项实验，可给基地带来革命. 听我多说两句.
Lesterson, what have you done? What have you done?
Lesterson, 你完成什么了? 你完成什么了?
I'll show you. Janley, now!
我给你演示一下. Janley, 开始!
It recognised the Doctor. It recognised him.
它认出了博士. 它认得他.
What's the matter, Doctor? Are you all right?
你怎么啦，博士? 有什么不舒服吗?
The fools. The stupid fools.
蠢人. 愚蠢之极.
You're scared! What can it do?
你害怕啦! 它能干什么?
Nothing yet.
目前还没有.
It knew who you were! It sounds ridiculous, but it did.
它知道你是谁! 虽然听起来很疯狂，但是真的.
(This creation is called, I understand, a Dalek... )
(这个生物叫做, 按我的理解, 叫做 Dalek...)
(Lesterson: Now, look at it. I have merely given it electrical power.
But it is capable of storing it..)
(现在看着, 我只不过给了一点电力, 但它能够储存它..)
Knew who I was.
知道我过去是谁.
The Dalek knows who you are.
Dalek 知道你现在是谁.
Moreover, it responds to orders. Turn around.
它还能对命令做出响应. 转一圈
Move that chair. Stop.
移动那个椅子. 停下
You see? Well, just think what this could do for our...
our mining program, our processing, packaging.
看见了吧. 想想这能给我们的挖矿, 流水线, 打包工作带来什么.
Dozens of labour jobs, Governor.
It may even supply the end to all this Colony's problems.
无数的劳工啊, 总督. 它甚至可以终结这个基地的所有问题.
Yes, it will end the colony's problems, because it will end the colony!
是的, 它可以终结这个基地的所有问题, 因为它可以终结这个基地!
I am your servant.
我-是-你的-仆人.
It... it spoke! Janley, did you hear it? It can actually talk!
它... 它说话了! Janley, 你听到了吗? 它真的会说话!
It can do many things, Lesterson.
But the thing it does most efficiently is exterminate human beings.
它能做很多事情, Lesterson. 但它干得最有效率的事情是终结人的生命.
It destroys them, without mercy, without conscience.
It destroys them. Utterly. Completely. It destroys them.
它毁灭人类, 毫不留情, 毫无内疚. 它毁灭人类. 绝对地. 完全地. 毁灭人类.
I am your servant. I am your servant....
我-是-你的-仆人. 我-是-你的-仆人
So Lesterson, they're even capable of speech!
Lesterson, 它们居然可以说话!
Yes. But then, why not? After all, they have a certain intelligence.
是的. 为什么不呢? 毕竟, 他们有一定的智力.
Yes I know, but...
是的我知道, 但是...
But is... is it... it is... an intelligence that we can control.
但是, 是不是... 我们可以控制住.
So what you want is permission to continue your experiments?
你想的无非就是获准可以继续你的实验?
Just think what it would mean if we were to set it to work in the mines. It could double our production overnight!
只要想想这意味着什么, 我们可以让他们去挖矿. 明天我们的生产力可以翻番了!
Consider the effects it could have on our whole economy.
想想这可能给我们整体经济带来什么效果.
Yes, and the effect of that on Earth... Yes. Yes, they could be very grateful.
是的, 还可以地球地球带来... 是的, 是的, 他们会很感激的.
I shall stop you. I will!
我会阻止你的，我会的!
All right Lesterson, permission granted.
好了 Lesterson, 我允许了
Permission? Permission for what?
允许? 允许什么?
To continue my work, Examiner.
继续我的工作啊, 监察员.
But... But didn't you all hear what I said? The Daleks must be destroyed!
但是... 但是你没听见我说什么了吗? Daleks必须全部毁掉!
Never!
绝不!
Very well. If not by my order - then by Earth's! Come Ben, Polly.
很好. 如果我的命令不好使 - 那地球的命令总可以了! 过来 Ben, Polly.
You're my servant, are you?
你是我的仆人, 是吗?
I... I am.
我... 是.
Very well. Immobilise yourself. Go on. I order it! Immediately!
很好. 关掉你自己. 快. 我命令! 马上!
Huh!
哈!
Lesterson.
Why did you stop obeying? You were given an order.
你为什么不遵守? 你已经收到命令了.
He has gone.
他-已经-走了.
Then you obey only...
你只遵守...
His order was wrong. I cannot serve human beings if I am immobilised.
他的-命令-是-错误的. 我-要是-关掉-自己-就-不能-服务于-人了/00
You gave me power. Your orders are right. I serve you.
你-给了-我-能量. 你的-命令-是-对的. 我-服务于-你.
Lesterson. Lesterson, it reasons. Just how limited is its intelligence?
Lesterson. Lesterson, 他会分析. 你不是说它智力有限吗?
Now, there is no cause for... for concern, Governor.
Just you wait until you see the amount of work it can do!
喔, 没理由担心这个, 总督. 你等着瞧它能做多少事情!
And now, I'm really going to put you through your paces. Follow me, Dalek.
现在, 我要让你经历你自己的生活了. 跟我来, Dalek.
I obey.
我-服从.
Excellent. excellent.
非常好. 非常好.
But I thought we were after the Daleks, not this control unit you've nicked!
我还以为我们在追查的是 Daleks, 而不是你在玩弄的这个控制盒!
Ah, yes!
He's a right little delinquent, isn't he?
他对这事不怎么上心, 是不?
Doctor, what on Earth are you up to?
博士, 你到底在干什么?
Ooh!
哦!
Ah! Now we're really getting somewhere!
啊! 我们真有点进展了!
Now, the Examiner was attacked, there can be no question of that.
监察员被攻击了，这是毫无疑问的
And the button grabbed by the Examiner was missing from your suit.
被监察员抓到手的纽扣，也是你衣服上不见的那个.
Yes, if you've got anything to add to that, you'd better say it now.
是的, 如果你还有什么补充, 你最好现在就说.
I didn't attack the man. I had no reason to. I was the one that sent for him!
我没有袭击他. 我没有理由. 他是我请求派来的!
You sent for him?!
你请求的?!
It was necessary. Under the circumstances, I'd hardly be likely to sabotage the radio communications.
这是有必要的. 鉴于这个情况, 我也不可能破坏电波通讯.
But... but why Quinn? Why?
不过... 为什么 Quinn? 为什么?
Because of the rebels!
因为那些叛乱分子!
The rebels! They're nothing more than one or two fanatics.
叛乱分子! 只不过有一两个狂热分子.
You know as well as I do that they...
你我都知道他们...
Unless you're trying to create trouble here - to undermine the Governor's position.
除非你是想制造些事端 - 想挖总督的墙脚吧.
Bragen, you'd better explain that.
Bragen, 你最好解释一下.
If you're removed, who takes your place? The Deputy Governor, of course.
如果你被除掉了, 谁顶你的位子? 当然是副总督
And that's the real reason behind all this trouble, isn't it Quinn?
这就是所有问题的真正原因, 对吧 Quinn?
Go on.
继续
You attack the Examiner in the mercury swamp and blame it on the rebels.
你在水银沼泽袭击了监察员, 嫁祸于叛乱分子
Then you sabotage the radio - blame that on the rebels too.
然后又破坏了电台 - 也归咎于叛乱分子.
Get him out of my sight!
把他带走!
Hensell, before you listen to these preposterous allegations...
Hensell, 在你听取这些荒谬的指控之前...
I chose Quinn myself. I trained him for the job. Why, in a few years time, he'd have had this seat!
Quinn 是我自己选的. 我培养他干这个工作. 为什么啊, 要不了几年时间, 他就能坐在这个位子上了啊!
Sometimes Governor, a few years is a long time to wait.
总督, 有时候, 几年时间也嫌太长, 等不了啊.
Oh, Bragen?
哦, Bragen?
Governor?
You will assume Quinn's duties. As of now, you are Deputy Governor.
你接替 Quinn 的工作. 从现在开始, 你是副总督.
Look Doctor, I don't want to appear dim, but how's this going to do the Daleks in?
看着, 博士, 我并不想看起来比较负能量, 但这跟 Daleks 有什么关系?
They think that Lesterson's the driving force, but I don't. The Daleks are using him.
他们认为是 Lesterson 有主导权, 但我觉得不是. Daleks 在利用他.
But how?
那怎么办?
Problem. Smash the Daleks, and the people here will lock us up or kill us.
有个问题. 砸碎 Daleks 的话, 这里的人会把我们锁起来或者干脆干掉我们
Let the Daleks go, and we'll all be exterminated.
任由 Daleks 乱来的话, 我们会被终结掉
We could just go back to the TARDIS. At least we'd be safe to think there.
我们可以回 TARDIS 去. 至少在那里是安全的.
Oh yes, that's coming on.
哦, 是的, 形势逼人啊
Oh, you talk to him, will you?
哦, 你会跟他说的, 是吗?
Doctor look, if you told us what you were up to, perhaps we could help you.
博士, 如果你告诉我们你要干什么的话, 也许我们能帮上忙.
Mustn't underestimate any of them.
Lesterson's a first class scientist, first class.
千万不能低估他们中的任何一个. Lesterson 是个一流的科学家, 一流的
He opened the capsule. He realised that the Daleks could be reactivated.
他打开了舱体, 还发现 Daleks 可以被重新激活.
Yeah, that could be the answer.
Let's kidnap Lesterson, and hide him away for a bit.
是, 那可能就是答案. 我们不如把 Lesterson 绑架了吧, 把他藏起来一阵子
Well, it would stop him bringing the Daleks back to life, wouldn't it?
这样就可以阻止他救活那些 Daleks, 对吧?
I thought it was pretty bright.
我觉得这个主意真不错.
There we are.
这下可以了.
What is it?
是什么?
What is it? It could be the answer to all our problems.
是什么? 可能是我们所有问题的答案.
Incredible! Well, let's move on to test fourteen.
难以置信! 好, 下面我们进行第14项测试.
I am ready.
我-准备-好了.
When sodium acts on ethyl alcohol, what is the resulting derivative?
把钠与酒精掺在一起, 会产生什么化合物?
Sodium ethoxide. C2 H5 ONa.
乙醇钠，C2H5ONa
Just five seconds, Janley! Just the time it took to speak the answer.
只需要5秒, Janley! 而且这点时间都用来念答案了.
Right too.
又答对了.
But of course it's right! Look, can you imagine
what kind of positronic brain this robot has, Janley?
当然是对的! 你能想象这个机器人用的是哪种正子脑吗, Janley?
Think of the store of knowledge that it must carry.
想想他得存有多少知识.
May I come in?
我可以进来吗?
What do you want?
你想干什么?
Oh, ah, just to see how you're getting on.
哦, 只是来看看你这里进展如何.
If you think...
如果你想要...
No, please! I'm... I'm not here to cause trouble.
I... I'm just interested, that's all.
不, 别这样! 我... 不是来找麻烦的. ... 我只是很有兴趣, 仅此而已.
You've done nothing but meddle and interfere
ever since you landed on Vulcan.
自你达到 Vulcan 以来, 除了干扰和干涉之外什么也没做过.
Well, I... I did give you permission to open up the capsule,
now didn't I? Please, carry on.
这个... 是我给了权限打开舱体, 是吧? 请, 继续吧.
And you won't try to stop me?
你不打算阻止我?
Stop you? No, of course not. We get off on the wrong foot, Lesterson, but..
阻止你? 不, 当然不. 咱们俩一开始就不怎么对付, Lesterson, 不过...
But I'm a reasonable man and... and I've been thinking, perhaps I was hasty.
不过我是一个讲理的人... 我在想, 也许是我太鲁莽了.
Well, if you... if you... if you really want to call a truce.
好吧, 如果... 如果你真想要休战.
A truce? My dear fellow, I... I'd like to be friends!
休战? 亲爱的家伙, ... 我期望可以成为朋友!
Yes. Yes. Very well, you may stay.
好. 好. 很好, 你可以呆着.
Oh, thank you. Thank you.
噢，谢谢你，谢谢你
Laboratory. Yes.
这里是实验室. 是.
All right, I can come now. Right.
好的, 我可以过来. 好.
I just have to slip out for a few minutes, Lesterson, alright?
我得出去几分钟, Lesterson, 可以吧?
Ah, yes, yes. Um, very well then. Examiner, shall we test its knowledge of physics?
啊, 可以, 可以. 唔, 那么, 监察员, 我们开始测试一下他的物理知识?
Oh, oh, splendid, splendid. Ah, huh, please, please, carry on.
哦, 太好了, 啊, 请开始吧.
Thank you. D... what is the First Law of Thermodynamics?
谢谢你... 热力学第一定律是什么?
When heat is transformed into any other kind of energy or vice versa,
the total quantity of energy remains invariable.
当-热能-转换成-其它-能, 或者-反过来, 能量-总和-保持-不变.
That is to say, the quantity of heat which disappears is
equivalent to the quantity of other kind of energy produced...
也-就是-说, 消失的-热能-和-新产生的-其它-类型的-能-在量上-是-相同的...
Fool! What do you think you're doing? I'm saving your life. Get out, get out!
笨蛋! 你以为你在干什么? 我会救你的. 出去, 出去!
Ah!... Ah!... Ah!... I have, ah, sustained no damage.
啊!... 啊!... 啊!... 我-扛住-了, 啊, 没有-受损
You were able to get away then?
你甩开他们了?
Yes. Lesterson's with the Examiner. And Hensell?
是的. Lesterson 和监察员在一起. Hensell 呢?
At a meeting of production managers. He left me in control.
在和产品经理们开会. 现在我说了算.
We could take over the colony now.
现在我们可以接管这个基地了.
No. No it has to be absolutely right. I don't want to take over
a colony full of rebels do I, Janley?
不. 必须做到万无一失. 我可不想接管一个满是叛乱分子的基地, 对吧, Janley?
Well, I don't know. You're making me help them.
我也不清楚. 是你让我帮助他们.
Only to stir them up to create enough trouble to get rid of Hensell,
and then... and then we crush them.
把他们搅乱, 多制造些问题, 就可以把 Hensell 搞下去了. 然后我们再镇压他们.
The whole colony will be grateful, and I'll be Governor.
整个基地都会感激我们, 我就是总督了.
Is that the gun you told me of?
这就是你跟我说过的那种枪?
Can you persuade the rebels this will help them?
你能说服那些叛乱分子, 说这对他们很有用吗?
Yes, Valmar thinks he can work in a switch to turn it on and off.
是的, Valmar 认为他可以做一个开关.
How powerful is it?
这有多厉害?
It killed Resno, Lesterson's assistant
它杀死了 Resno, Lesterson 的助手
And Lesterson believes that Resno's simply shaken up - taking a few days off.
Lesterson 还以为 Resno 只是晕倒了, 需要休息几天而已.
And the body?
尸体呢?
In the mercury swamp. Lesterson was the indirect cause of Resno's death.
扔进水银沼泽了. 其实是 Lesterson 害死了他.
It's a good hold over him if he makes trouble.
这是个不错的把柄, 不怕他制造麻烦了
I'll give this to Valmar then?
那我把这个交给 Valmar 去了?
Yes.
好
When do we move?
我们什么时候行动?
I need another card in my hand. The Examiner bothers me.
我手里还缺一张牌. 那个监察员让我不放心.
I thought Quinn was the danger.
我以为 Quinn 才是危险.
Uh, not any more. The Examiner is no fool. No, there has to be something else.
哦, 不再是了. 那个监察员不是傻子. 不对, 这里还得搞点事儿.
Well?
怎样?
Well, he's not in the laboratory, Lesterson's by himself.
他不在实验室里, 只有 Lesterson 一个人.
Hmm. He must have gone another way. Can I leave it you? I'm going to go back to the rest room.
嗯. 他肯定从别的路走了. 把你一个人留在这里行吗? 我打算回休息室去.
Well, but...
不过...
Well, somebody's got to clear it up.
总有人得把它打扫一下吧.
Okay.
好吧.
Hello there.
哈罗.
Hello. Um, you're Lesterson's assistant aren't you?
哈喽. 唔, 你是 Lesterson 的助手吧?
Yes. You're not looking for the Examiner are you?
是的. 你不是在找监察员吧?
Well, do you know where he is?
那你知道他在哪儿吗?
Yes, he's waiting to get a message through from Earth.
He's in the Communications Room.
他在等一条地球来的消息, 他在通讯室.
Umm...
唔...
Oh, you'll find it easy enough. Look.
Around, then to your right, in the next block.
哦, 你会发现很简单的.  拐过去, 在你的右手边, 下一个区就是.
Thanks very much.
太感谢了.
Doctor? Anyone here?
博士? 这里有人吗?
She said she was coming back here. She knew the way,
and she wouldn't have wandered off. I know she wouldn't! Oh!
她说了她回这里来的. 她认识路, 也不会乱转, 我知道她不会的. 噢!
Ben, if you were a Dalek what would be your next move?
Ben, 如果你是一个 Dalek 你下一步要做什么?
I'm talking about Polly.
我说的是 Polly.
Oh, no, no, no, no. She's a clever girl, but she couldn't answer this.
哦, 不不不. 她是个聪明的女孩儿, 但她回答不了这个.
But she is missing!
她失踪了!
Oh, no, no, no.
哦, 不不不.
Oh, yes, yes, yes, yes!
哦, 是是是是!
No, no, no! She's looking around, there's a lot to see in the colony. She's interested. I like that.
不不不! 她四处逛逛而已, 这里有好多东西可以看. 她对这些很感兴趣. 我喜欢这一点.
Come on.
来吧
Where are we going?
我们要去哪儿?
To report it. If we make a fool of ourselves, I don't care! We report it!
去报告. 如果我们要傻等, 我可不想! 我们去报告!
Yes, yes, yes. I managed to stop that fool of an Examiner just in time.
还好. 我总算及时阻止了那个傻蛋监察员.
You know there are some people here who believe that you're an enemy.
你知道这里有些人会认为你是敌人
I am your servant.
我-是-你的-仆人
What does this machine do?
这台-机器-是做-什么-的?
You know, it's amazing. You have an almost human interest and curiosity.
你看, 很神奇的. 你有着人类一样的兴趣和好奇心.
A Dalek is bet... is not the same as a human.
Dalek-比人类...跟人类-不太-一样
If I am to help, I must know everything.
如果-要我-帮忙, 我得-知道-所有-事情.
Yes. Yes, of course.
是的, 当然.
What is this machine?
这个-是-什么-机器?
It computes meteorite storms as they approach our weather satellites.
它是用来计算陨石风暴的, 以免它们损坏我们的气象卫星.
How accurate is it?
它有-多-准确?
About, ah, seventy percent. It helps to cut down on our satellite losses.
大约70％. 它对于降低卫星损失很有帮助.
Daleks can build pu... computers with one hundred percent accuracy.
Daleks-可以-建造-计算机-准确度-达到-百分之百.
One hundred percent?
百分之百?
If you provide materials and our own power unit, a computer will be built.
如果-你能-提供-材料, 并给-我们-提供-能量, 计算机-将会-造好.
A hundred percent. That would be an enormous saving for the... for the colony!
百分之百. 那对于这个基地将是巨大的节约!
Then, you will get the materials?
那么-你能-拿到-材料-吗?
I'll go and speak to the Governor at once.
我马上去跟总督说.
I will be ready to dictate the blueprint when you return.
当你-回来-的时候-我-将把-蓝图-准备好.
Huh, huh. Oh, that's marvellous!
嚯. 那真是太棒了!
You agreed we'd go and see Bragen.
你同意我们去找 Bragen 的.
Hmm? Power.
唔? 能量.
Come on then!
快点啊!
Now the energy intake for Daleks should be the cube...
Daleks 的能量入口应该是那个方块...
Lesterson!
Eh?
哦?
He just went past. That means we can get into his laboratory again.
他刚走过去了. 也就是说我们又可以进他的实验室了.
But we're looking for...
但我们要去找...
Oh, come along, Ben. Come along.
哦, 来吧, Ben. 过来.
There's somebody in there.
这里有人.
What are you doing here?
你在-这里-干什么?
Stand aside. Servants shouldn't question.
站一边去. 仆人不应该管这个.
Entry is restricted.
入口-是-受限的.
Not for me it isn't. "Accord every access". I've got a badge.
对我不是. "授予一切权限". 我有这个徽章.
That is an order.
这是-一项-命令.
A Dalek order. Short circuit the generator, Ben.
Dalek 的命令. 去把生成器弄短路了, Ben.
Ah!... Ah!... Ah!... Ah!... Ah!... Stand back!
啊!... 啊!!... 靠后站!
Don't be frightened of it Ben. It's not armed.
I'm going to see what it was doing in there.
别怕它 Ben. 它没有武器了. 我倒要看看他打算在这里做什么.
Ben, let's get out of here!
Ben, 我们快出去!
Fool. Lesterson must have reactivated them.
蠢啊. Lesterson 一定重新激活他们了.
Yes. When I say run, Run!
是的, 我说跑的时候 - 跑！
I have sent the human being for materials.
我-已经-让人类-去-准备-材料了.
And power?
还有-能量?
Yes. Power we can turn into static, then we will conquer.
是. 我们-能把-能量-转换为-静电, 然后-我们-就可-征服.
We will conquer... We will conquer... We will conquer...
我们-将要-征服... 我们-将要-征服... 我们-将要-征服...
But if you didn't do it Lesterson, then the Dalek must have
used your power supply and reactivated the others itself.
但是如果不是你干的 Lesterson, 那么 Dalek 肯定是自己用你提供的电源激活了其它几个
I was going to do that anyway.
我正要去激活它们呢.
Are you off your head, mate? Those two are armed!
你脑子秀逗了, 伙计? 他们是带武器的!
Then we turn off the electricity, disarm them, and then everything is safe again.
那我们关掉电力供应, 解除他们的武装, 不就万事大吉了.
I've already explained to you.
我已经跟你解释过了.
Stop these arguments, both of you. I've had enough.
停止这些争论吧, 你俩都别说了, 我受够了.
I've every confidence in Lesterson.
He has carte blanche for the Daleks from now on.
我对 Lesterson 有绝对信心. 从现在开始他将获得全权委托.
But they must be destroyed!
但他们必须被销毁掉!
Bragen, I'm making a tour of the perimeter.
I put you in direct charge here.
Bragen, 我要下去巡视了, 在此期间这里你说了算
See that Lesterson gets everything he wants, will you?
确保 Lesterson 这里想要什么就给他什么, 好吧?
I shall need a permanent guard on my laboratory, Bragen.
我实验室还需要一个保安, Bragen.
Don't worry about the Examiner. I think I can keep him quiet.
别担心监察员. 我想我能让他保持安静.
Greed and ambition, that's all it is.
贪婪, 野心勃勃, 那就是它们的本性.
Wait till they find out what their precious production figures have cost them!
等着吧, 看看他们美妙的产品图能带给他们什么代价!
Oh, I want to see you.
哦, 我正要去找你呢.
What about?
为了什么?
Well it's Polly, she's missing. We can't find her anywhere.
是 Polly, 她失踪. 我们在哪儿都找不到她.
I'll tell one of my men to make enquiries. It shouldn't take long to find her.
我安排一个人去找找, 应该很快就可以找到她.
Ah, thanks.
多谢了.
Examiner, some of my men have found a body in the mercury swamp.
It was the body of a middle-aged man.
监察员, 我的几个手下在水银沼泽里发现了一具尸体, 是一个中年人的.
What is that to do with me?
这跟我有什么关系吗?
You're the Examiner - or maybe you're not.
你是监察员啊 - 除非你不是.
Just exactly what do you mean by that?
你这么说是什么意思?
Who are you? Quinn's friends? Come to stir up rebellion?
你是谁? Quinn 的朋友? 是来制造骚乱?
There's only one possible way that you could know I'm not the Examiner.
如果你认为我不是监察员, 那只有一种可能.
Yeah, by knowing what the real Examiner looked like!
是的, 那就是知道真正的监察员长什么样!
Exactly, Ben. Exactly! Only two people knew of his arrival on this planet. Myself and his murderer.
很对, Ben. 很对! 只有两个人知道他抵达这个星球时的情形：我和杀他的人.
That's enough!
够了!
Is it? Doctor, we've got to tell the Governor.
是这样? 博士, 我们去告诉总督.
Do you think he'll believe you? I'll soon convince him
that you murdered the man yourself. You stole the Examiner's badge.
你觉得他会相信你? 我很快就可以让他相信是你杀了那个人, 还偷了那个人的徽章.
Then why don't you arrest us? Because there's a doubt isn't there?
Because it might, it just might, go against you.
那你为什么不逮捕我们? 因为这里还有疑问, 对不? 因为有可能不往你想的方向发展.
All right, all right, so neither of us wants to make a move.
But you leave Lesterson alone - and the Daleks!
好吧, 好吧, 我们谁也不想先动. 但你们离 Lesterson 远点 - 还有 Daleks!
He'd make a right Father Christmas, wouldn't he?
他要做一个圣诞老人, 对不
Oh, I'd rather fight a hundred of his sort than just one Dalek.
哦, 我宁可跟一百个他这种人斗, 也不想碰到一个 Dalek.
Listen to this. "The girl is safe. She will remain so
as long as you leave the Daleks alone".
听听. "女孩儿很安全. 只要你们远离 Daleks, 她就是安全的".
And did you disarm the other two?
你解除了另外两个的武器?
Yes. We are your servants. We do not need guns.
是的-我们-是-你的-仆人-我们-不-需要-武器.
I'm very glad. I knew the Examiner was wrong about you.
我很高兴. 我知道监察员看错你们了.
Did you get our materials?
你-给-我们-带来-材料-了-吗?
Yes. Everything you need you can have.
是的. 你们想要什么都行.
And a power plant?
还有-一个-电厂?
Everything.
都行.
We will get our power.
我们-将会-获得-能量(权力?)
We will get our power. We will get our power. We will...
我们-将会-获得-能量．我们-将会-获得-能量. 我们-将会...
Turn back the power supply.
重新-打开-电力-供应
I will, I will. But I want you to remember that I control you.
我会的，但我要你们记住，是我控制你们
We are your servants.
I know. Remember it. I gave you each a special charge to bring you back to life.
我知道，记住这点：我给了你们每个充了电，这才让你们复活了
Any further power you need must come from this generator.
And I control it. Is that clear?
你们还需要电力的话，都得靠这个发电机来. 是我来控制它，清楚了吗?
We obey.
我们-服从
Where are they going?
他们要去哪里?
To await your orders, master.
静候-你的-命令 主人
Good. Have you completed the blueprints for the meteor storm computer?
很好. 那个陨石风暴方面的计算机，你完成设计图了吗
It is ready.
已经-好了
Oh, it's marvellous! I'm glad we understand each other.
噢, 太棒了! 我很高兴我们达成了共识
We understand the human mind.
我们-了解-人类-想法
Isn't that finished yet?
还没完成吗?
Nearly.
快了
About time. This work should have been completed long before this.
还算及时. 这项工作早应该完成了
Well, I did the best I could!
我已经尽了最大努力!
Well, it isn't good enough!
是，但还不够!
Then get someone else, Bragen.
那你找其他人吧, Bragen.
Be careful! I shall be watching you, Valmar, after this - now get out!
小心点! 我会盯着你, Valmar, 从现在开始 - 现在给我出去!
What does this intrusion mean?
这样闯进来是什么意思?
I'm sorry, Bragen. I tried to stop them.
抱歉, Bragen. 我没能拦住他们
Intrusion? It's no intrusion. We're just returning the various calls that you made.
硬闯进来? 不是硬闯. 你不是要见我们吗，我们就来了
This guard tried to tell us you were busy. You're not a bit, are you?
这个保安跟我们说你一直都忙，但你一点也不忙，是不?
All right - I'll see them.
好了，我见他们
Oh, what a nice new uniform. Very smart, very smart. I would like a hat like that.
喔, 新制服很不错啊. 很醒目. 很醒目. 我想要一顶类似的帽子.
Well, what do you want?
你们想要干什么
Some joker has kidnapped Polly and sent us this note.
某些小丑绑架了 Polly ，送来了这张字条
Yes.
哦
Well, we want to know what you're doing to find her.
我们想知道你打算怎样找她
Now that the communications are restored we can start a search.
现在通讯已经恢复了，我们可以展开搜索
Yeah, I can just imagine what kind of job you'll make of that.
Haven't you heard anything yet?
好，我能想象你将会怎样做. 你没有听说什么吗?
The planet is a large one.
这个星球很大
So! They've given you the run of the colony, have they?
他们已经让你来运作整个基地，是吧
We obey. Do I bring liquid for your visitors?
我们-服从. 需要-给你的-客人-准备-饮料吗?
No. They won't be staying much longer.
不必了. 他们不会呆多久.
Look, Doctor, if he's not going to help us, we'll have to search for Polly ourselves.
看, 博士, 如果他不打算帮我们, 我们就得自己去找寻 Polly 了.
Sound advice. Why don't you, Doctor?
好主意, 为什么不去呢, 博士?
Ah, ah, Examiner.
哦, 是监察员.
I wonder how much longer they'll be able to move around on these floors?
我很好奇他们怎么能够在这些地板上转来转去?
Eh?
呃?
Static you see. They need a constant supply of static from the floor, some sort of electrical field.
静电你看. 他们需要地板持续提供静电, 某种电力场.
Doctor. Why should he...?
博士, 为什么他会...?
It's madness!
这太疯狂了!
What is?
什么?
Letting them run around like this.
允许他们像这样乱跑.
Hey, wait a minute! Bragen had one acting as a servant, and we've just left him!
嘿, 等一下! Bragen 已经有一个做仆人的了, 我们刚离开那里!
One Dalek in Bragen's office - three Daleks just gone down the corridors. That makes four!
一个 Dalek 在 Bragen 的办公室 - 三个 Daleks 刚走过了走廊. 总共就是四个!
Where did the fourth one come from?
第四个哪里来的?
Well, Lesterson can't have been making them.
Perhaps there were more in the capsule than we thought?
Lesterson 不可能在制造它们. 说不定舱体里面还有一些, 而我们不知道?
Janley?
What is it?
什么事?
The Daleks. They've given me another list of materials they need.
那些 Daleks. 他们又给了一份清单, 说它们需要这些材料.
Let me see. We've got all those things?
我看看. 我们有这些东西吗?
Yes, but why these quantities, Janley? Why?
How can they have used up all the materials I gave them?
有, 不过为什么要这么多, Janley? 他们怎么可能已经用完我给他们的材料了?
What is it? D... why, it's only a matter of a few hours ago.
到底是什么情况? ... 才过了几个小时而已.
They're building new things for us.
他们在为我们建设新东西.
Yes, well I don't want them to do anything without consulting me.
What is it they do inside there?
是的, 我不想他们做事之前不问我的意见. 他们到底在那里面做什么?
You're worrying too much.
你担心得过头了.
Look Janley, say what you like, but I'm beginning to believe
that the Examiner is right about the Daleks.
Janley 你说说你的看法. 不过我开始觉得监察员对 Daleks 的看法是对的
Their original thinking terrifies me.
If we can control them, fine. But if not...
他们的想法吓着我了. 如果我们能控制住他们, 那还好. 但如果不能...
Yes?
怎样?
Then I shall have them destroyed. It's too dangerous.
那我就要把他们销毁. 这太危险了
The Examiner knows something about them that we don't.
I'm going to ask his advice.
监察员知道一些我们不知道的事情. 我要去问问他的建议.
I wouldn't bring the Examiner into it if I were you.
如果我是你的话, 我不会把监察员扯进来.
And why not?
为什么不呢?
You want him to find out about Resno?
你想让他发现 Resno 的事吗?
Oh, a little accident. How is he? Is he better?
哦, 一点小事故. 他怎样了? 好些了吗?
He's dead.
他死了.
What are you talking about? You told me he was...
你在说什么呢? 你告诉我说他只是...
You're busy with the experiments on the Daleks.
你当时在忙着搞 Daleks 的实验.
But you should have told me. But... but the body - it'll have to be reported.
但你应该告诉我啊. 不过... 尸体怎么办 - 这事得上报.
Don't worry, no one will find the body.
别担心, 没人会发现尸体.
Oh Janley, you've done a terrible thing.
哦 Janley, 你干了一件很糟糕的事情.
The experiments on the Daleks were more important.
Daleks 的实验更加重要.
More important than human life? No. No, I won't accept that.
比人命更重要? 不, 不, 我不会接受这个.
You will. You must! Your carelessness was the cause of Resno's death.
你会的. 你必须! 是你的粗心大意导致了 Resno 的死亡.
You murdered him. It's only your word against mine.
是你杀死了他. 除了我的证词, 你找不到别人证明
I won't be blackmailed by you!
我不会被你勒索的!
All I want is for you to go on as you are.
Scientific discovery can't stop dead, Lesterson.
我想要的只是你继续干你的事. 科学发现不应该在死亡面前停步, Lesterson.
I told the guard that no-one was to be allowed in.
我告诉过保安没人可以进来.
"Accord every access" remember?
"授予一切权限" 记得吗?
We're looking for Polly.
我们正在找寻 Polly.
Well, she isn't here, and I haven't seen her.
这样啊, 她并不在这里, 我也没看见过她.
Well, she's been kidnapped.
她被绑架了.
Oh, it sounds a little unlikely.
哦, 听起来不太可能啊.
Oh it does, does it? Well, we've got this note which tells us so.
很可能, 对不? 看, 我们还收到了这样字条, 上面是这样说的.
I'm very sorry, but I don't know anything about it.
我很抱歉, 这事我什么也不知道.
Lesterson?
Yes?
什么?
You haven't been building Daleks, have you?
你没在建造 Daleks 吧, 有吗?
Building? No I wouldn't know how to begin.
建造? 不, 我都不知道怎么开始.
And there were only three in the capsule?
舱体里面当时只有三个?
Yes.
是的
Well we've just seen four. One in the Governor's office and three in the corridor!
但我们刚才看见了四个. 一个在总督的办公室, 三个在走廊!
But that's not possible!
但那是不可能的啊!
There's only one explanation. The Daleks are reproducing themselves!
这只有一个解释. Daleks 正在自我复制!
These things are machines. How could they reproduce?
他们只是机器而已, 怎么能自我复制呢?
Machines! What makes you think they're just machines.
机器! 凭什么你认为他们只是机器.
The Daleks are brilliant engineers.
Nothing is beyond them given the right materials.
Daleks 是非常卓越的工程师, 只要有足够的材料, 没谁比他们厉害.
What?
什么
I said nothing is beyond them given the right materials.
我说只要有足够的材料, 没谁比他们厉害.
Oh...
噢...
Lesterson, what's the matter?
Lesterson, 怎么回事?
Oh...
噢...
Leave him alone. He's just been overworking, that's all.
让他一个人呆会儿. 他劳累过度了, 仅此而已.
Well, he looks bad.
嗯, 他看来比较糟糕.
Will you both go away. Guard! It's you - badgering him with questions.
你俩能不能离开. 保安! 就是你 - 拿些问题来纠缠他
You've done nothing but hound him ever since you arrived on Vulcan.
自从你到 Vulcan 来, 除了干扰他你什么事情都没干.
Bragen's orders were that no one was to be admitted.
Bragen 的命令是不让任何人进来.
Yes, but I thought that the... the Examiner.
是的, 但是我觉得 ... 监察员....
He attacked Lesterson. Get them out of here. Both of them.
他攻击了 Lesterson. 把他赶出去. 把他们俩.
He did not attack Lesterson.
他没有攻击 Lesterson.
Out, do you hear?!
出去, 听见了吗?!
All right, all right.
好吧, 好吧.
Janley here. Tell Valmar to come over to the lab right away. Good.
我是 Janley. 告诉 Valmar 马上到实验室来一趟. 好
Well, we're still no nearer finding Polly. What are we hanging about here for?
我们还是没有找到 Polly. 在这里闲着做什么呢?
Ben, I've found a message in code.
Ben, 我在文字里看到了一个消息.
Oh, I can't do crosswords.
哦, 我不会做填字游戏.
Meeting tonight, 2000 hours. R O C K E T - Rocket.
R O O M - Room. P. Rocket Room P!
今晚会议, 晚上 20:00. R O C K E T - Rocket. R O O M - Room. P. 火箭室 P !
It's the rebels way of calling a meeting.
Only tonight we're going to be there - early.
这是叛乱分子召集会议的方法, 今晚我们得去那里 - 得早到.
Yeah, maybe we're nearer finding Polly than I thought.
嘢, 也许能有线索找到 Polly.
Now, we're going to demonstrate something.
You section leaders can pass on what you've seen.
现在, 我们要展示一点东西. 你们这些分队头目可以把你们看见的事情回去传达一下
So far, we've been concerned with testing the strength of the Governor with a few acts of sabotage.
到目前为止, 我们还只是进行了几次破坏活动, 主要是为了试试总督的力量
But now, we're ready to take over.
但现在, 我们准备要夺权了.
What is that thing? I've seen them moving about,
but all we've been told is that it's a machine Lesterson discovered.
这是什么东西? 我看他们来回转, 但只是告诉我们说是 Lesterson 发现的一种机器.
Valmar?
Well, Lesterson removed the armaments of the Daleks he discovered.
看, 这些 Daleks 是 Lesterson 发现的, 他移除了他们的的武器装备
I've rearmed this one, but with a controlling device.
我又重新给这个装上了, 但多接了一个控制器.
We can regulate the fire power and turn it off and on whenever we choose.
我们随时可以调节枪的火力, 甚至关闭它.
Shall we have the demonstration now?
我们可以演示了吗?
This screen is two inch thick tungsten steel. Right, Valmar.
这个屏幕是两英寸厚的钨锰合金. 开始吧, Valmar.
Fire at the screen.
对着屏幕开火.
Quiet! You must keep quiet. We're too vulnerable here.
安静! 你们必须保持安静. 你们太容易被发现了.
But, you can't control a thing like that. It'll turn on us!
但是你控制不住这样的东西, 它会攻击我们的!
No it won't.
不, 它不会的.
Now, what about the girl?
现在说下, 那女孩怎么办?
We've got her safely locked up. Never fear.
我们把她锁起来了, 不用担心
I think the best thing for us to do is...
我觉得我们最好是...
Hear that? Maybe they'll say were she is.
听到了吗? 说不定他们会说出把她藏哪儿了
Who's there?
谁在那里?
You stay there, I'll distract them. Find out where Polly is.
你待在这里, 我去引开他们. 找出 Polly 在哪里
No!
不!
Help! Help!
救命! 救命!
The guards will have heard that! Come on we've got to get out of here!
保安会听见的! 我们得赶紧离开这里!
You might as well come out. We know you're there.
你最好也出来吧. 我们知道你在那儿
Bragen!
Of course. Who else is fitted to be leader of the rebels?
当然. 否则还有谁适合当这些人的领导?
No doubt you want to be leader of the Daleks too.
毫无疑问你也相当 Daleks 的领导.
I am the leader of the Daleks.
我的确是 Daleks 的领导
Well see if you can stop this one from killing me.
看看你能不能阻止这家伙杀我
Stop! You heard me, that's an order. Turn away. Fetch the guard.
停止! 你听到了, 这是命令. 转身, 去吧保安叫来
I obey.
我-遵命
You hope to have it both ways, Bragen.
你还真会两条腿走路啊, Bragen.
But how will you look in front of the Governor, when I explain your dual role to him?
不过到了总督面前你会变成什么样子, 一旦我向他揭示你的双重身份的话?
The Governor will hardly listen to an impostor.
总督不太可能相信一个冒名顶替者的话
An impostor? How do you propose to prove that?
冒名顶替者? 你打算怎么证明这个?
My guards are now going to produce the body of the real Examiner from the mercury swamp.
我的保安正在水银沼泽打捞那个真监察员的尸体
The one you murdered.
被你谋杀的那个
The one you pretended to be.
被你假冒的那个
Murder's a far worse crime than impersonation.
谋杀罪比冒名顶替严重多了
Yes, but you can't prove I'm a murderer, while I can prove that you're an impostor.
是的, 但你没法证明我是个杀人犯, 而我却可以证明你是假冒的.
Ah... Oh...
啊... 噢...
You sent for me?
你-叫我-过来?
Take up a position at the communications room. Watch and report.
在-通讯室-找个-位置  负责-观察 发现-问题-就-报告
I obey.
我-服从
They're conspiring together! Oh, why didn't I realise?
他们在一起密谋什么! 噢, 我居然没发现?
The Examiner was right. They are evil!
监察员是对的, 他们是邪恶的!
There are four. They can't be reproducing!
的确有四个. 它们不可能在自我复制吧!
Dalek nine complete.
Dalek-九号-完成
Check.
检查通过
Dalek ten complete.
Dalek-十号-完成
Check.
检查通过
Dalek eleven complete.
Dalek-十一号-完成
Check.
检查通过
Dalek twelve complete.
Dalek-十二号-完成
Check.
检查通过
Dalek thirteen complete.
Dalek-十三号-通过
Check.
检查通过
Dalek fourteen complete.
Dalek-十四号-完成
We are the Daleks! We are the new race of Daleks!
我们-是-Daleks, 我们-是-新一代-Daleks!
What's the matter? What is it?
怎么回事, 这是干什么?
Are you ill?
你生病了吗?
They're in there - making themselves! Duplicating!
它们在里面 - 制造它们自己! 在复制!
What? What are you talking about?
什么? 你在说什么?
I started this, opening the capsule!
是我挑起的, 打开了太空舱!
Lesterson!
Don't try to stop me!
别想阻止我!
What happened?
They forget that I control them! I gave them life back again
它们忘记了是该由我控制! 我重新给了它们生命复活了它们
And now I've taken it away! Finished! Stopped it!
现在我要拿走! 结束他们! 阻止它们!
The Daleks...
那些 Daleks...
Evil! Horrible! I know what I'm going to do! Laser torches!
邪恶! 恐怖! 我知道我要干什么了! 激光束!
Melt them down! I'm going to melt the Daleks down to pools of metal!
把他们融掉! 我要把这些 Daleks 融化为金属池!
You won't Lesterson!
你不会的 Lesterson!
Ah, do you think I care what you can do?!
啊, 你觉得我还顾忌你能做什么?!
Go on, tell everybody I was responsible for Resno's death!
去吧, 告诉每一个人是我害死了Resno!
I don't care! I'm going to wipe out the Daleks!
我不在乎! 我要抹平这些 Daleks!
Yes, tell everybody all about me! I'm still going to...
I'm going to... wipe out the Daleks!
是的, 告诉每一个人我的事. 我还是要...我要... 抹掉这些 Daleks!
Get me the Examiner. But I've got to talk to him!
I've got to, don't you understand?!
但我要跟他谈话! 我必须要, 听不懂吗?!
How did you get there?! I cut off the power!
你怎么过来的?! 我已经把电源切断了!
We can store power. We will soon have our own.
我们-可以-储存-能量 我们-很快-会有-自己的-能量
Own power?!
自己的能量?!
Why was the capsule door closed?
为什么-舱门-关闭了
Own power?! Ahh!
自己的能量?! 啊!
Seal off the capsule's secret entrance.
封闭-舱体-秘密-入口
I obey.
我-服从
Wait!
等等!
No more than three Daleks to be seen together at any one time.
每次-不要-三个-以上-Daleks-同时-出现-被人-看到
I obey.
我-服从
We are not ready yet to teach these human beings the law of the Daleks.
我们-还没-打算-教导-这些-人类-学习-Daleks-的法律
Well, Bragen - these trips are becoming more and more demanding.
唉, Bragen - 这一趟趟的似乎越来越吃力了
I didn't expect you, Governor.
没想到你会出现, 总督
Ah, I had as much as I could stand. Well? What's been happening here?
啊, 再往外跑我就有点受不了了. 怎么样? 这里发生了什么?
One moment.
等会儿.
I asked you a question, man.
我问你问题呢, 伙计.
I heard you.
我听见了.
Look, your work can wait. You can hand over to me tomorrow.
I want to hear about the Examiner.
嘿, 你的工作可以先放放. 明天转交回我就行了. 我想听听监察员的情况.
He's an impostor, Governor. Possibly a murderer as well.
他是个假冒的, 总督. 还很可能是个谋杀犯
We have just discovered the body of the real Examiner in the mercury swamp.
我们刚在水银沼泽里面发现了真监察员的尸体.
I hope you're sure of your facts, Bragen.
我期望你说的情况都是事实, Bragen.
Quite sure.
相当确定.
This could have far-reaching consequences.
这可能会有长远的后果.
As far as I am concerned, there's nothing more to be said.
So if there's nothing further...
就我所知, 这没什么需要补充的了. 如果没有其它事情...
Nothing further! Who the devil do you think you're talking to?
Stand up when you're speaking to me man!
没有其它! 你以为你在跟谁说话? 跟我说话的时候站起来!
I prefer to remain seated.
我更愿意继续坐着.
Do you now?! We'll soon see about that. Guards!
是吗?! 我们就来看看. 保安!
Take this man out of my office.
把这个人带出我的办公室.
Did you hear what I said? That's an order!
你们没有听见我说的吗? 这是命令!
You forget, my dear Hensell. They're not your guards - they're mine.
你忘记了, 我亲爱的 Hensell. 他们不是你的保安 - 他们是我的.
I am the Governor!
我是总督!
No. Not now. I am.
不. 现在不是了. 我才是.
Oh, I see. Your guards, eh?
哦, 我明白了. 你的保安, 呃?
Yes, Quinn warned me about your guards,
but we all took them too lightly, didn't we?
是了, Quinn 警告过我关于你的保安的事情, 但我们都没太重视?
When the people hear that I am being kept a prisoner in my own capital...
果人们听说我在自己的首府被囚禁起来了...
The people will do exactly as they are told, Hensell.
他们只会按照我们告诉他们的情况做出反应, Hensell.
It will, of course, be easier for them if you co-operate with us.
当然, 如果你与我们合作的话, 事情会更容易一点.
You're the last man I expected to see here.
你是我最没想到会在这里见到的人
Well your imprisonment hasn't been entirely wasted.
It's brought your enemy out into...
你被关起来倒不是完全没好处, 至少把你的敌人暴露...
Bragen? I've known that all along.
Bragen 是吧? 我一直都知道的.
Yes. But, ah, did you know that he was the leader of the rebels?
是的. 但是你是否知道他是叛乱分子的头目
Hmm. Work's by sound, does it?
唔. 靠声音驱动的, 是吧?
Wait there. Guards, dismissed.
等着. 保安, 你们可以出去了.
So Bragen, you want my co-operation, do you?
怎样, Bragen, 你需要我的合作, 对吧?
It would save bloodshed. I might even let you keep the title of Governor.
这样能少流些血. 我甚至可以让你继续留着总督的头衔.
Might you now?! I'll tell you what you will do. You'll order
your guards to disarm and place yourself under arrest immediately!
你会吗?! 我来告诉你你将会做什么. 你让你的保安都解除武装, 立即逮捕你自己!
So you reject my offer? I thought it a generous one in the circumstances.
这么说你拒绝我的提议? 我还觉得在当前情形下这是个挺慷慨的提议呢.
What circumstances?
当前什么情形?
Look at this.
看看这个.
What is it?
这是什么?
The reason that the colony is now mine.
这就是为什么这个基地现在是我的.
Is it a weapon of some kind?
这是某种武器?
I'll arrange a demonstration for you. Do you still refuse my offer?
我给你安排一个演示吧. 你还是拒绝我的提议吗?
I will not be intimidated.
我不会妥协的.
Of course not. In character to the last, Hensell. Kill him!
当然不. 执迷不悟啊, Hensell. 杀了他!
Why do human beings kill human beings?
为什么-人类-杀死-人类?
Get on with your work!
去干你的活去!
Yes, master. I obey.
是的-主人  我-服从.
Yes, obey me! From now on, I will have complete obedience from everyone!
是的, 服从我! 从现在开始, 我要每个人都要绝对服从!
I'll have to check the cable circuit now. Otherwise, it's just as you asked for.
现在我还得检查一下线缆回路. 否则的话, it's just as you asked for.(FIXME)
Very well.
很好
Why can't you carry on with the power you're drawing from the colony? Why go to all this trouble?
为什么你们不直接利用你从基地抽取到的能量呢? 费这个劲做什么?
Until now, we have had to recharge from the colony supply.
到目前-为止, 我们-还是-要用-基地-电力-充电
With static power, the Daleks will be twice as useful.
采用-静电, Daleks-将会-加倍-有用.
Valmar, quick!
Valmar, 快点!
What's the matter?
什么情况?
The Governor's back.
总督回来了.
What about the girl?
这女孩儿怎么办?
Leave her.
别管她了.
I will follow you.
我-要-跟着-你.
What for?
为什么?
I am your servant.
我-是-你的-仆人
Come on.
得了
An electrical circuit of their own supplying static electricity!
I wonder how much longer we've got?
他们自己的静电供电线路! 我好奇我们还有多少时间?
I didn't realise they'd have a circuit of their own.
我没有意识到他们将有自己的供电线路.
Doctor, look out!
博士, 快看!
Are you all right?
你没事吧
Well done! Who was the man who went outside just now?
做得好! 刚才出去的那个人是谁?
Valmar. He's been working for the Daleks.
Valmar. 他一直在给 Daleks 干活.
On their static power supply.
搭建他们的静电供应系统.
Doctor, they've got Ben.
Doctor, 他们抓了 Ben.
Yes, I know. He ran away so that I could... Oh well, it's a long story
是的, 我知道. 他跑出来是为了让我... 噢, 这就说来话长了
But don't worry. That boy can take care of himself!
不过别担心. 那小子可以照顾他自己!
Did you hear that? That won't help.
你听到了吗? That won't help.
Get out! All of you!
出去! 你们全部!
What about you?!
你怎么办?!
But Doctor! Oh...
但是, 博士! 噢...
Go!
走!
Have they escaped?
他们-逃跑-了吗?
Yes, return to capsule and report.
是的-回到-舱内-然后-报告.
I obey.
我-服从
We are to wait here until the human beings fight among themselves.
我们-在-这里-等待-直到-人类-自己-内部-打起来.
Then we will strike.
然后-我们-将会-攻击.
And exterminate! Exterminate! Exterminate! ...
终结 ! 终结 ! 终结 !
But why? Why was he killed?
为什么他会被杀?
I can answer that.
我能回答这个.
He wanted to destroy the Daleks, so one of them killed him. Now, I'm declaring martial law.
他想要销毁 Daleks, 所以其中一个就杀死了他. 现在, 我宣布戒严
Martial law! What good do you think that will do against the Daleks?
戒严! 你觉得这对于对付 Daleks 有什么作用?
The Daleks will do as I tell them.
Daleks 会听命于我
We shall see, shan't we.
那我们就看看吧, 看吧
Take them away.
把他们带走.
Exterminate! Exterminate! Exterminate!
终结! 终结! 终结!
Orders received. Exterminate all humans!
指令-已收到. 终结-所有-人类!
Exterminate all humans!
消灭-所有-人类!
Exterminate! Annihilate! Destroy! Daleks conquer and destroy!
终结! 灭绝! 摧毁! Daleks-征服-并摧毁!
Daleks conquer and destroy! Daleks conquer and destroy! ...
Daleks-征服-并摧毁! Daleks-征服-并摧毁!...
Move on!
继续走!
The Dalek!
有 Dalek!
What about it?
那怎么了?
Can't you see it's armed?
你看不出来他是有武器的?
Keep moving!
继续前进!
This area is restricted.
这个-区域-已经-禁止.
On whose authority?
谁授权的?
Silence!
安静!
Repeat. This area is restricted.
重复. 这个-区域-已经-禁止.
Obey or you shall be exterminated.
服从-否则-你们-会被-毁灭.
I thought they obeyed us?
我以为是它们服从我们?
What do we do now, Doctor?
我们现在怎么办, Doctor?
This way.
这边走.
They will be exterminated.
他们-会被-毁灭.
We've won. The revolution's over. I'll pass the word to Valmar, Kebble and the rest.
我们已经赢了. 革命已经结束了. 我将传话给 Valmar, Kebble 和其他人.
Wait. The revolution is not quite over yet.
等等. 革命还没完全结束.
What more can we do? Hensell's dead, you're the new Governor. The battle's over.
我们还要做什么? Hensell 已经死了, 你成了新总督. 战斗也结束了.
Not quite. You mentioned Kebble, Valmar and that rabble. Well now they must be dealt with.
不完全. 你提到了 Kebble, Valmar 等一群人. 他们必须要处理掉.
But those are our own men.
但那是我们的人.
Huh, huh. Of course.
呵, 呵. 当然.
I don't understand.
我不明白.
Do you think I can ever be secure in that chair while that rabble are still loose?
如果这群闹事的人放任自流的话, 你觉得我这把椅子能坐稳吗?
They rebelled against Hensell yesterday. Tomorrow it'll be my turn.
他们昨天反叛的是 Hensell, 明天就可能轮到我了.
Well, let them rebel. Tell them the guards have taken control.
算了, 让他们闹事, 跟他们说保安已经掌握控制权了
Let them attack, and then we can crush them, utterly!
让他们进攻, 然后我们就可以镇压他们, 一举歼灭!
You say "we".
你说了＂我们＂.
Yes. We've come a long way together you and I. You going to back down now?
是的. 我们一路走了这么久, 你和我. 你现在要回那边去吗?
Couldn't you just arrest them?
你不能仅仅只是逮捕他们吗?
Everyone must be killed.
所有人必须死.
Now!
现在!
What have you brought me in here for?
你把我带来这里做什么?
Quiet!
Whose side are you on anyway?
你到底是属哪边的?
I thought I was going to be on the winning side.
我想我以前属于要得胜的一边.
What changed your mind?
怎么改变主意了?
Bragen. The colony's become too small for him. He wants us out of the way now.
Bragen. 这个基地对他来说太小了. 他现在不想要任何人挡他的道.
Yeah, well it often happens that way, mate, when you follow blokes like him.
是的, 这种事最后经常是这样, 伙计, 当你跟着他这样的家伙.
Look, I'm going to try and get your friends here, if I can. So wait here.
看, 我要去试着把你的朋友们找来, 尽我所能. 你等在这里.
People of Vulcan. This is your new Governor talking to you.
Vulcan 人民请注意. 现在是你们的新总督在讲话
I have to announce that Governor Hensell has been murdered by the rebels.
我不得不告知大家总督 Hensell 已经被叛乱分子谋杀了
I have taken control temporarily, until order is restored.
我已经暂时获得了控制权, 直到秩序恢复
People living on the perimeter and in the interior can stay calm.
住在卫星城和内城的群众请保持冷静
We know who the murderers are.
I shall keep you informed of events as soon as I am able,
我们已经知道凶手是谁. 我一旦获知任何消息, 将尽可能及时知会大家
So listen for the signal to watch your communication sets. That is all.
所以请留意你们的通讯设备中的信号. 广播结束.
Ah! There you are.
啊! 你在这里啊.
- Ben!
- I knew you'd be all right!
- Ben! - 我就知道你会没事的!
Polly - you okay?
Polly - 你还好吧?
Oh, yes.
哦, 还好
Did Valmar find you, then?
Valmar 去找你们了, 碰到了吗?
Valmar? No.
Valmar? 没有.
What's this about Valmar?
又有 Valmar 什么事?
Well it seems Bragen's gone power-mad. He wants the rebels to revolt, then he can finish them off.
是这样, 看起来 Bragen 已经疯狂了. 他故意让叛乱分子起来闹事, 然后他好再把他们消灭掉.
The Daleks won't care who they fight. They'll exterminate every human being on this planet.
Daleks 不会在乎跟谁打. 他们会毁灭这个星球上的每一个人.
Doctor, please let's go back to the TARDIS.
Doctor, 求你了, 我们回到 TARDIS 去吧.
Quinn. Keep them both here.
Quinn. 看住他们俩.
Well, wait a minute, Doctor!
喂, 等一下, 博士!
All right. All right.
好吧, 好吧.
Orders received. Daleks commence extermination.
命令-已收到. Daleks-开始-终结!
Exterminate! Exterminate! Exterminate!
Down everyone!
都趴下!
Don't come any nearer.
别往前走了.
What do you mean?
你什么意思?
I overheard your conversation with Bragen.
我无意中听到你跟 Bragen 的谈话
But you can't stand up to the Daleks, so your plan will come to nothing.
但你们是没法站起来对抗 Daleks的, 因此你们的计划将会落空.
Not my plan - Bragen's.
不是我的计划 - 是 Bragen 的.
But that's the same thing.
但那是一回事.
Not any more.
不再是了.
You expect me to believe that?
你期望我能相信?
I came here to do exactly what you've done.
我来这里是要做你已经做了的事情
Let Bragen see what the Daleks are like. He doesn't know how strong they are.
让 Bragen 看看 Daleks 到底是怎样的东西. 他不知道它们有多强悍.
He's got to be stopped.
必须得有人阻止他.
You will lead us to the middle of your party of human beings.
你们-必须-带我们-去到-你们-人类-中间.
Yes.
是的
We will fight for you.
我们-将-战斗-为你们
Believe me, Val, it's the only way to save all our lives.
相信我, Val, 这是救我们性命的唯一方法.
Did you know that the Daleks are duplicating?
你知道那些 Daleks 在自我复制吗?
Yes.
知道
But we are your friends.
但是-我们-是-你们的-朋友.
We will serve you.
我们-将要-服务于-你们.
Take us to the centre of your group.
带-我们-去-你们-小组-中间.
Can we trust them?
我们能信任他们吗?
We must! The guards have orders to wipe us out. We must use the Daleks. Come on.
必须得! 保安们已经收到命令要把我们彻底消灭. 我们必须得利用 Daleks. 快来.
Doctor!
博士!
The window. Does it open?
这个窗户. 能打开吗?
I dunno.
我不知道.
It had better, or we're done for! Out you go.
最好能, 否则我们就完蛋了! 你快出去.
Ah!... Ah!... What's happening?
啊!... 啊!... 发生了什么?
The Daleks. They're teeming all over the corridors.
We've got to get back to Lesterson's lab.
Daleks. 他们在走廊集结, 都快挤满了. 我们得回到 Lesterson 的实验室去.
This is Governor Bragen speaking. A group of rebels is attempting to take over the colony.
现在是总督 Bragen 讲话. 一组叛乱分子试图占领基地
It is the duty of all loyal citizens to help the guards resist.
所有忠诚的市民有责任帮助保安抵抗他们.
Stay in your homes. Order will be restored. Listen to my bulletins.
请待在家里, 等待秩序恢复. 保持关注我的简报.
The rebels are using the Daleks against our people!
叛乱分子正在利用 Daleks 反击我们的人!
Well, get back and fight! Why do you come running to me? What do you think your guns are for?
那就回去战斗啊! 你跑到我这里来干什么? 你觉得你们的枪是干什么用的?
Well, the guns don't work against them!
但是, 枪对它们不管用啊!
Get back and fight them!
回去, 打他们!
There, and there!
那儿, 那儿!
Over there!
还有那儿!
No! No! Over there! They're our people!
不! 不! 那边! 那是我们的人!
Cut the Dalek gun off!
把 Dalek 的枪卸了!
No! Ah!...
不! 啊!...
I told you to cut the gun off!
跟你说把他们的枪卸了!
I did!
已经切断了啊!
You've killed our own people!
你杀死了我们自己的人!
We have to dismantle the gun, that's all.
我们必须得拆除它们的枪, 只能这样.
Oh, look at it.
噢, 快看.
Your usefulness is over.
你们的-用途-已经-结束.
Come on!
快来!
Quick, Val. Come on!
快, Val. 快来!
Doctor, it's stupid to hide in here!
博士, 躲在这里太蠢了!
Well, do you fancy your chances outside in the corridor? No thanks.
那你想到走廊上去试试运气吗? 谢谢了.
The answer must be here somewhere.
肯定得有别的什么方法.
Ssssh!
嘘!
Ah!...
You must be absolutely quiet. They know everything that's going on.
Everything! They even know what you're thinking.
你们必须绝对安静. 它们知道当前的所有事情, 所有! 它们甚至知道你在想什么.
Where do they get their power from, Lesterson?
他们的能量从哪里来的, Lesterson?
Ah, I tried to turn the power off. But they were miles ahead of me.
啊, 我试过去切断电源, 但离我太远了.
Marvellous creatures. You have to admire them.
神奇的生物啊, 你不得不佩服他们.
But we've got to stop them!
但我们要去阻止它们!
Oh, it's too late for that. They're the new species, you see.
哦, 干这事儿太晚了. 它们是一个新的种族, 明白不.
Taking over from homo sapiens. Man's had his day. Finished now.
开始从智人手中接管世界了. 人类终有这一天, 都结束了.
The static circuit is nearly complete.
静电-线路-就快-完成.
Soon we can abandon the power we are using.
马上-我们-可以-抛弃-正在-使用的-电能.
The humans are being exterminated.
人类-将要-被-毁灭.
Did you hear that? They're going to use their own power!
你听到了吗? 它们要开始使用它们自己的能量!
- No!
- Come on!
- Don't be a fool
- come on!
Take it easy, Polly.
别怕, Polly.
Can't we do anything?! They're murdering everybody, one by one!
我们不能做点什么吗?! 他们在谋杀所有人, 一个接一个!
You've done all this. Why did you give them power in the first place?
都是你造成的. 一开始你为什么要给它们提供能量?
Well, I could control it, you see.
哦, 我当时可以控制住的, 你看.
And then Janley got one of her men - Valmar, I think it was,
yes - and he rigged up a secret cable.
然后 Janley 找了一个她的人 - Valmar, 好像是这个名字 - 他安装了一个秘密线缆.
It's carrying power directly from the colony's supply.
那个线缆直接由基地电厂提供电力.
Where? Where is it, Lesterson?
哪儿? 在哪儿, Lesterson?
Valmar's the only one who can answer that. Or the Daleks of course.
Valmar 是唯一能回答这个问题的人. 当然 Daleks 也能
They know everything. Yes, you should ask the Daleks.
它们知道所有事情, 是的, 你问 Daleks 也可以.
Then we must find Valmar.
那么我们必须找到 Valmar.
No! You stay here and look after Polly.
不! 你留在这里照顾 Polly.
I'll go.
我过去（过来，快点! 啊----）
You'll have to leave her now, Valmar.
你必须舍她而去了, Valmar.
Section One? Where's your report? Are you there Section One?
一分队? 你们的情况如何? 你们还在吗一分队?
Section Two? Section Two? Why don't they answer? Can you hear me Section Two?
二分队? 二分队? 为什么不回答? 你们能听到吗二分队?
Section Three? Oh, why don't they answer? I'm their Governor. Why don't they answer?
三分队? 噢, 为什么他们不回话? 我是总督. 为什么他们不回话?
This is Bragen speaking. I'm speaking to the Daleks.
这里是 Bragen. 我现在同 Daleks 讲话.
Daleks, listen to me. I am the Governor. You must work for me.
Daleks, 听我说, 我是总督. 你们必须为我工作.
Do not trust the rebels. I will give you whatever you want.
不要相信叛乱分子. 我会给予你们想要的任何东西
But immobilise your guns. This is the Governor speaking.
但要立即放下武器. 这里是总督在讲话.
He's nuts, trying to talk to the Daleks.
他是个蠢蛋, 居然想跟 Daleks 谈条件.
Lesterson, what's in that cupboard?
Lesterson, 这个柜子里面是什么?
Nothing. I think It's quite empty.
Well, come on, Polly, we'll be safe in there, love.
正好, 来吧, Polly, 我们躲在这里面比较安全, 很好.
Do you hear me, Daleks?! You will obey my orders!
你们听到我的话了没, Daleks?! 你们必须服从我的命令!
No use, Bragen. The Daleks have stopped obeying your orders.
没用的, Bragen. Daleks 早就不服从你的命令了.
Ah! Guards!
啊! 保安!
Dead! The Daleks have killed them. You still have your guard units
in the interior. How long will it take them to get here?
都死了! Daleks 杀死了他们. 你在内城里还有几个保安小队. 他们到这里要多久?
That depends.
看情况.
Well, get them!
赶紧啊!
Well, they will be intercepted by the Daleks.
但他们也会被 Daleks 拦截住.
Exactly! It will draw them away from here and give the Doctor a chance to deal with them.
正是! 这会把它们从这里引开, 给博士去寻找对付它们的机会.
I refuse to allow my guards to be sacrificed.
我拒绝让我的保安们去做牺牲.
In that case the Daleks will destroy everything on this colony.
那样的话 Daleks 会把这个基地所有的东西都毁掉.
Guards. This is Bragen speaking. All units will report immediately to the capital.
保安. 我是 Bragen. 所有小组马上到首府报告
Be prepared to face the rebel Daleks.
注意可能会遭遇造反的 Daleks.
Ben! Polly!
Doctor, did you hear what Bragen said?
博士, 你听到 Bragen 说的了吗?
Yes, I did.
是的, 我听到了.
Well I only hope the Daleks do go for the guards.
我只能期望 Daleks 都跑到保安那里去.
A lot of the Daleks went out just now.
好多 Daleks 刚才出去了.
Good, because we're going inside. Come on Valmar.
很好, 因为我们要进去. 快来 Valmar.
Ben, give us that spare cable over there. Polly, keep watch at the door.
Ben, 把那根闲置的线缆给我们. Polly, 你负责在门口放哨.
Well, you know what you're doing?
你知道你在做什么吧?
Of course I do!
我当然知道!
Well, why can't you just take all the plugs out and cut the power off?
嗯, 为什么你不直接把插头都拔掉, 这样不就都切断了?
Because I prefer to do it my way!
因为我更喜欢按我的方法来!
Look out!
小心!
Static power is being stored. We can dismantle the human electric system.
静电-能量-已经-储存. 我们-可以-拆除-人类-电力-系统.
The law of the Daleks is in force.
Daleks-法律-已经-生效
Extermination of humans.
终结-所有-人类.
Our cables have been moved.
我们的-线缆-已被-移动.
And I could tell you who did it!
我可以告诉你们是谁干的!
What were you doing in there?
你-在-这里-干-什么?
I want to help you.
我想帮助你们.
Why?
为什么
I am your servant.
我是你的仆人
We do not need humans now.
我们-不-需要-人类-现在
Ah, then, but you wouldn't kill me. I gave you life.
啊, 这样的话, 你也不应该杀我. 是我给了你们生命.
Yes, you gave us life.
是的, 你-给了-我们-生命.
Ah!... Ah!... Ah!... Ah!... Ah!...
啊...啊...啊...啊...啊...
Out of control..
失去-控制
What happened to it?
它怎么了?
I don't know.
我不知道
It seems that your friend, the Examiner, was successful after all.
看来你的朋友, 那个监察员, 获得了最终胜利.
Now I shall restore law and order on this planet.
现在我要恢复这个星球的法律和秩序了.
Not your law, Bragen. That's finished for good.
不是你的法律, Bragen. 一切已经结束了.
You'll obey me, or...
你要服从我, 否则...
Your day is over, Bragen. No one will obey you now.
你的日子已经结束了, Bragen. 现在没人再服从你了.
I'm still the Governor, and you will...
我仍然是总督, 而且你将...
Valmar.
He was a murderer.
他是个凶手.
Enough of guns.
流了够多的血了.
There's a lot of clearing up to be done. We will rebuild together.
What is the extent of the damage?
还有好多收尾的工作要做. 我们得一起来重建. 损毁的程度怎样?
Oh, I don't know if its repairable. The whole electrical system.
哦, 我不知道还能不能修好. 整个电力系统都...
Are you all right?
你没事吧?
Oh, he's OK. The clot knocked himself out.
哦, 他没事. 他被砸晕了而已
It's a miracle. How did you do it?
这是个奇迹. 你怎么做到的?
Eh? What happened?
呃, 发生了什么?
You destroyed the Daleks, that's what you did!
你摧毁了 Daleks, 那就是你做的!
Did I do that?
是我干的?
You know you did!
是的, 你知道的!
You used the power from the colony's electric supply - overfed it
- and blew up their temporary static circuit. Well didn't you?
你用光了基地供电系统的电力 - 让它们过载了 - 炸掉了它们的临时静电电路. 干得不错啊?
Did I do all that?
是我干的吗?
You may have stopped the Daleks,
but have you any idea of the damage you've done to the colony?
你是阻止了 Daleks, 但你就没想到你对这个基地造成的损害吗?
Oh. There was a blow back, was there?
哦. 免不了有点后坐力, 是吧?
A blow back? Our power supply has been destroyed!
It'll be months before we can get things back to normal.
后坐力? 我们的电力供应被毁掉了! 可能需要数月我们才能让事情回归正常.
Valmar!
That is unfortunate.
那太不幸了.
But did it have to be this way?
但你必须得用这个方法吗?
I did a lot of damage, did I?
我造成了很大的破坏, 是吧?
Come on.
得了
I think we'd better get out of here before they send us the bill.
我觉得我们还是赶紧离开这里吧, 赶在他们送账单过来之前.